Kushagra Seth

Software Developer In Test

Contact Details

Address

Ashok Vihar Phase-3, New Delhi, Delhi, 110052

Phone

+91-9650022646

E-mail

kushagraseth.1996@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/kushagra-seth

www

https://linkedin.com/in/kushagra-seth

www

https://linkedin.com/in/kushagra-seth

Skills

Java, Python, C++

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Express JS

Python Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Keras, NLTK, TensorFlow 2.0, Matplotlib, NumPy, Pandas

Databases: SQL Server, MySql, CouchBase, PostgreSql

API Automation: ReadyAPI, Postman, Karate

UI Automation: Selenium, TestNG, WDIO

Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Jenkins, JIRA

Methodical **Software Developer in Test** experienced in software development processes and optimal testing strategies. Helps teams produce exceptional products by offering in-depth quality assurance support. Open and clear communicator with good multitasking skills, organized nature and strong attention to detail. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy. Well versed with Agile and Scrum methodologies.

Work Experience

2019-07 - Current

Software Developer in Test

Cvent India Pvt. Ltd, Gurugram, Haryana

- Currently working on CVENT Conference Product earlier known as Lanyon Conference.
- Operated under Agile and Scrum frameworks to complete releases every week and well-organized sprints.
- Collaborated with product team to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Collaborated on all stages of systems development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Configured and worked with Jenkins Jobs for implementing CI/CD methodology.
- UI Automation using Selenium with Java/TestNG and WDIO.
- API Automation using ReadyAPI, Postman and Karate.

2018-06 - 2018-07

Software Development Intern

SS Supply Chain(3SC) Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Gurugram, Sohna Road, Gurgaon, Haryana

- Created online web application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.
- Developed this web application for verification and auditing of freight bills for Vendor and Retailers.
- Created front-end dashboard to show due payments within th current month.
- Created Master tabs and Report tabs for easy maneuverability within transport management dashboard.

2017-06 - 2017-07

Data Science Intern

Team Computers Pvt. Ltd, Gurugram, Gurgaon, Haryana

- Designed data model and workflow on ALTERYX Designer.
- Cleaned, filtered and merged sample dataset for past one year.
- Calculated Turn Around Time (TAT) for each contracted inquiry from dataset of past one year.
- Calculated vehicle inquiry status for each dealer [New inquiry, Contracted, Under Follow Up, Delivered or Invoiced].
- Calculated Total Predicted Inquiries and generated cumulative dataset i.e., predicted number of vehicles Honda dealers will sell based on outstanding inquiries.

Education

2015-08 - 2019-07

B. Tech: Information Technology

Maharaja Agrasen Institute Of Technology (GGSIPU) - Delhi

Graduated with 8.7/10 CGPA

2012-04 - 2015-04

High School: Non-Medical With Computer Science

Salwan Public School - New Delhi. Delhi

- 10th Grade: 9.8/10 CGPA
- 12th Grade: Graduated with 90% marks

Research Paper

K. Seth, S. S. Patwal, A. Misra and A. Goel, "CLIMATE CHANGE STANCE CLASSIFICATION using Artificial Neural Networks(ANN), Convolutional Neural Networks(CNN), RNN-LSTM & CNN-LSTM," *JETIR*, vol. 6, no. 5, pp. 35-46, 2019. http://www.jetir.org/papers/JETIR1905A04.pdf

Phase - 1 using Machine Learning Classification Algorithms:

• Classification problem solved using TF-IDF Feature Extraction model & SVM classification model.

Phase - 2 using Deep Learning Networks:

- Implementation of Principal Component Analysis (PCA) technique to improve the accuracy of the model.
- Word Embedding models used 300-dimension pre-trained GloVe, 100-dimension pre-trained Word2Vec with CNN-LSTM.

Phase - 3 using Transfer Learning:

- Model pre-trained on freezed sentence embeddings.
- Model fine-tuned using the BERT model developed by Google.